<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natasha Fox on Filmaday</title>
    <link>https://filmaday.com.au/tags/natasha-fox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natasha Fox on Filmaday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 11:48:43 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://filmaday.com.au/tags/natasha-fox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>“Below Her Mouth” review: An authentic exploration of sex and vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/below-her-mouth-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/below-her-mouth-review/</guid>
      <description>Arriving at the Sydney Mardi Gras Film Festival following a run through the international film festival circuit, including TIFF, I was lucky enough to attend a screening of “Below Her Mouth” followed by a Q&amp;amp;A with director April Mullen. This was the second screening of the film during the festival, with both 800-seat sessions sold out weeks in advance. Leading up to the screening, I had been eager to see the film, as much had been made of Mullen’s representation of female sexuality in a sensual and truthful manner, which is rarely seen on the silver screen and if it is, usually distastefully presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Her Best Films of 2014</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/her-best-films-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/her-best-films-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>Before I jump into my 2015 best of list I’d like to begin by apologising to our legions of readers (ie. Mum) for how late this post is. I can assure you there is a good reason behind my tardiness - I just couldn’t bring myself to write my list when there was tickets to see Birdman sitting in my pocket. Way back at the beginning of December ‘14 we had booked “advanced screening” tickets to see Birdman in the first week of January 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>