<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Filmaday</title>
    <link>https://filmaday.com.au/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Filmaday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 11:48:43 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://filmaday.com.au/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>“Random Acts of Flyness” Review: Terence Nance&#39; inventive exploration of the modern black experience.</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/20181103-random-acts-of-flyness-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/20181103-random-acts-of-flyness-review/</guid>
      <description>Terence Nance made one of the great films of the new century with &amp;ldquo;An Oversimplification Of Her Beauty&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s depressing that his output is constrained by an industry that continually fails to reward filmmakers like him.
&amp;ldquo;Random Acts of Flyness&amp;rdquo; continues in a similar mode. Playing a fictionalized version of himself, Terence navigates the modern black experience, but expands upon his original cinematic work by inviting other writers and directors to create the work with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Unforgiven” Review: Clint Eastwood attacks the violent heart of American mythology</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/20181103-unforgiven-clint-eastwood-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/20181103-unforgiven-clint-eastwood-review/</guid>
      <description>A terribly sad repositioning of the American West mythology and a clear-headed meditation on the unspeakable violence, racist and misogynist culture that sat at the heart of the American frontier.
Eastwood has become a politically polarizing figure and his films are co-opted or rejected through politically narrow readings.
While playing hyper-masculine, hyper-violent characters, Eastwood has also chipped away—in front of the camera and behind—at the empty symbols and rhetoric those characters represent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Below Her Mouth” review: An authentic exploration of sex and vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/below-her-mouth-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/below-her-mouth-review/</guid>
      <description>Arriving at the Sydney Mardi Gras Film Festival following a run through the international film festival circuit, including TIFF, I was lucky enough to attend a screening of “Below Her Mouth” followed by a Q&amp;amp;A with director April Mullen. This was the second screening of the film during the festival, with both 800-seat sessions sold out weeks in advance. Leading up to the screening, I had been eager to see the film, as much had been made of Mullen’s representation of female sexuality in a sensual and truthful manner, which is rarely seen on the silver screen and if it is, usually distastefully presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Lion” review: A banal retelling of an astonishing story</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/lion-review-a-banal-retelling-of-an-astonishing-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/lion-review-a-banal-retelling-of-an-astonishing-story/</guid>
      <description>“Lion”, the feature debut by Australian filmmaker Garth Davis, is a missed opportunity as his limited cinematic vision fails to translate the extraordinary sequences and themes of the film’s story.
It’s a film about randomness, insignificance and love without the visual imagination to convey any of these ideas on the screen. It is imbued with perfunctory information and little else.
“Lion” tells the extraordinary story of Saroo Brierley (played by Sunny Pawar as a child and Dev Patel as an adult), who becomes lost in India, lives in the streets of Calcutta, is adopted by a Tasmanian couple and grows up in Australia before finding his hometown via Google Maps and returning as an adult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Joe Cinque’s Consolation” review: A lack of curiosity fails to inspire the mind or eye</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/joe-cinques-consolation-review-a-lack-of-curiosity-fails-to-inspire-the-mind-or-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/joe-cinques-consolation-review-a-lack-of-curiosity-fails-to-inspire-the-mind-or-eye/</guid>
      <description>Note—for the purpose of clarity, references to the real-life people will be with their last name, and references to the fictional characters will be their first name.
A film dealing with the events leading up to Joe Cinque’s death should not be this shallow. In 1997, Anu Singh was charged and later convicted of the manslaughter of her then boyfriend, Joe Cinque. Singh laced Cinque’s coffee with rohypnol before injecting him with a fatal dose of heroin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Hacksaw Ridge” review: An unimaginative throwback that appeals to the worst instincts of worship and jingoism</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/hacksaw-ridge-review-an-unimaginative-throwback-that-appeals-to-the-worst-instincts-of-worship-and-jingoism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/hacksaw-ridge-review-an-unimaginative-throwback-that-appeals-to-the-worst-instincts-of-worship-and-jingoism/</guid>
      <description>“Hacksaw Ridge” arrives ten years after Mel Gibson’s previous directorial effort, the near-excellent “Apocalypto”, and follows an industry-imposed absence from filmmaking after repeated personal indiscretions. Gibson returned to the screen as an actor in 2010’s “Edge of Darkness”. Gibson’s difficulties in securing Hollywood financing may still be an ongoing issue, as he returns here with an Australian cast and production on a very American subject. This decision ultimately harms the impact of Gibson’s artistry as it fails to connect its characters to any artistic or cultural relevance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Shallows” review: A film that offers little to think about and even less excitement</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-shallows-review-a-film-that-offers-little-to-think-about-and-even-less-excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-shallows-review-a-film-that-offers-little-to-think-about-and-even-less-excitement/</guid>
      <description>“The Shallows” arrives in theatres with a great deal of anticipation. The film’s marketing campaign has focused on its minimal setting and straight forward narrative—a drawn out game of cat and mouse as a surfer tries to make it out of the ocean without getting eaten by a shark—and Blake Lively’s figure in a bikini. This is, it seems, enough to generate great anticipation.
Written by Anthony Jaswinski (“Kristy”) and directed by Jaume Collet-Serra, whose previous directorial efforts include the Liam Neeson vehicles “Unknown” and “Non-Stop”, the film proper delivers on the marketing campaign’s promise and little more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Approaching the Unknown” review: Artistry limits the dramatic understanding of human existence</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/approaching-the-unknown-review-artistry-limits-the-dramatic-understanding-of-human-existence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/approaching-the-unknown-review-artistry-limits-the-dramatic-understanding-of-human-existence/</guid>
      <description>Mark Elijah Rosenberg writes and directs his first feature, “Approaching the Unknown”, with a keen appreciation of scientific ingenuity and human life but without an understanding of the artistry required to translate these ideas into a cinematic experience.
The story focuses on astronaut William Stanaforth (Mark Strong), as he embarks on a near two-year journey to Mars to make the foundations of a human colony on the planet. He is followed by Emily Maddox (Sanaa Lathan), who leaves several weeks after Stanaforth, I can only presume as a redundancy, given that Stanaforth seems very much capable of running his own operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Michael Haneke&#39;s compositions and patriarchal criticism in “The White Ribbon”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/exploring-michael-hanekes-compositions-and-patriarchal-criticism-in-the-white-ribbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/exploring-michael-hanekes-compositions-and-patriarchal-criticism-in-the-white-ribbon/</guid>
      <description>Michael Haneke’s &amp;ldquo;The White Ribbon&amp;rdquo; is one of those films that I fell in love with from the opening shot, much like his earlier film &amp;ldquo;Cache&amp;rdquo;. The strength of this film comes from its visual compositions—you could watch it silently and still work out what the film is trying to say.
Set in rural Germany before World War I, we are introduced to the townspeople through a series of accidents. The Doctor gets caught up in tripwire on his horse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time capsule — “True Grit” &amp; “Black Swan” reviews</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/time-capsule-true-grit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/time-capsule-true-grit/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across the original copies of my reviews for &amp;ldquo;Black Swan&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;True Grit&amp;rdquo; which were published on a now-defunct site. From another life. Best left there.
Black Swan
 With his last film The Wrestler, director Darren Aronofsky sliced through the sheen and entertainment of semi-professional wrestling to reveal it as the bleeding art it can be. Black Swan is a similar vehicle, only this time he takes away the pomp and romantic grandeur of ballet to reveal the battered and bleeding artists behind the dancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Batman V Superman: Dawn of Justice” review: A film too timid and limited in vision to really matter</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice-review/</guid>
      <description>On September 11, two thousand and one, four commercial airliners were hijacked in the United States and used to attack key US landmarks. Three days later the United States Congress passed the Authorised Use of Military Force (AUMF) bill, authorising use of the US Armed Forces against those responsible for the attacks.
Nine days after September 11, then American President George Bush told Congress “every nation in every region now has a decision to make: Either you are with us or you are with the terrorists”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Witch” Review: A thrilling dream that explores the heart of fanaticism and American fundamentalism</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-witch-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-witch-review/</guid>
      <description>“The Witch” arrives in Australian cinemas thirteen months after its debut at the Sundance Film Festival, during which time the initial, glowing reviews have helped establish the film’s own mythicism. Robert Eggers’ “The Witch” is a horror film in the most classical sense.
Banished from a pioneering New England settlement, a Puritanical family resettle in a small clearing surrounded by woods. Not long after arriving, the eldest daughter, Thomasin (Anya Taylor-Joy) is playing with her newborn brother when he vanishes practically before her eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Zoolander 2” Review: A Film That Mostly Wastes the Energy of its Actors</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/zoolander-2-review-a-film-that-mostly-wastes-the-energy-of-its-actors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/zoolander-2-review-a-film-that-mostly-wastes-the-energy-of-its-actors/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Zoolander 2&amp;rdquo; occupies strange territory—both in its own art and in its place within the popular culture of two-thousand and sixteen.
It’s interesting to think about what Ben Stiller, the film’s writer and director, thinks of its place in the world and why he felt an updating of the adventures of Derek Zoolander was relevant to today’s audience. That’s not to say the film doesn’t have its own lifeforce—for it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“An” Review: Naomi Kawase&#39;s Wonderful Film about Sadness &amp; Need</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/an-review-naomi-kawases-wonderful-film-about-sadness-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/an-review-naomi-kawases-wonderful-film-about-sadness-need/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the history of Japan cherry blossoms have been a symbol of life, death and rebirth.
Japanese filmmaker Naomi Kawase’s latest film, &amp;ldquo;An&amp;rdquo;, from a script written by Kawase based on the book by Durian Sukegawa, explores these themes in modern Japan. Kawase wants us to think about how life—its pulse and energy—exists within societal and architectural structures governed by straight lines. Kawase has always been interested in how people and chaos can play out despite the conformity of their surrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Macbeth” retold as an insubstantial war film</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/macbeth-retold-as-an-insubstantial-war-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/macbeth-retold-as-an-insubstantial-war-film/</guid>
      <description>As someone who’s always been a Shakespeare enthusiast, I was excited to see a new telling of &amp;ldquo;Macbeth&amp;rdquo; and had been following the making of this film for some time. I would like to clarify that while I am an enthusiast, I am in no way a purist. The idea of modern storytellers bringing Shakespeare’s works to a modern audience always excites me and if they can re-interpret the stories in such a way that encourages new interest, that’s even better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Spotlight” review: The Work of Journalism is at the Centre of Tom McCarthy’s Moving &amp; Necessary Film</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/spotlight-review-the-work-of-journalism-is-at-the-centre-of-tom-mccarthys-moving-necessary-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/spotlight-review-the-work-of-journalism-is-at-the-centre-of-tom-mccarthys-moving-necessary-film/</guid>
      <description>Access is a recurring theme in modern journalism discourse—direct access to source, access to content and access to the abilities to churn out journalistic content at an alarming rate—where it is no longer a matter of if but when we reach peak content. The argument against this mass of mass media follows the thinking that the ease of access—the ease in which we can consume and create journalistic content—means the work of journalism is easier than before and it’s output is more lightweight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Star Wars: The Force Awakens” Review: The full J.J. Abrams experience</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/star-wars-the-force-awakens-review-the-full-jj-abrams-experience-includes-the-good-and-the-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/star-wars-the-force-awakens-review-the-full-jj-abrams-experience-includes-the-good-and-the-bad/</guid>
      <description>A galaxy far, far away still has plenty of cinematic thrills to deliver if the audience expectation and early reactions to the new Star Wars film have been any indication. Directed by J.J. Abrams and written by Abrams with the help of “The Empire Strikes Back” writer Lawrence Kasdan and Michael Arndt, “Star Wars: The Force Awakens” is an attempt to put greater distance between the George Lucas prequels and realign the franchise with the original trilogy—films that are now contained within their own cinematic mythology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Creed” Review: A cinematic marvel, Ryan Coogler’s greatest wonder with “Creed” is the black lives he puts on screen</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/creed-review-a-cinematic-marvel-ryan-cooglers-greatest-wonder-with-creed-is-the-black-lives-he-puts-on-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/creed-review-a-cinematic-marvel-ryan-cooglers-greatest-wonder-with-creed-is-the-black-lives-he-puts-on-screen/</guid>
      <description>Ryan Coogler’s “Creed” is a rhapsodic exploration of life imbued with the filmmaker’s own social conscience and intelligence.
His previous film, “Fruitvale Station”, was a commanding work, both angry and vital without ever being truly inventive. Building on the confident storytelling in that film, Coogler has taken his muse, Michael B. Jordan, and created a work that is completely attuned to the time of its making—a film infused with social awareness and understanding of the need for a diverse representation of American lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random screens in the final episode of “The Knick”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/random-skips-through-the-final-episode-of-the-knick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/random-skips-through-the-final-episode-of-the-knick/</guid>
      <description>Screenshots taken after randomly clicking along the timeline in chronological order.
The final episode of season 02 of the &amp;ldquo;The Knick&amp;rdquo; finds Thackery requiring intestinal resection, a procedure he eventually sees fit to perform himself to a horrified gallery. Cornelia finds out that she didn&amp;rsquo;t know her brother as well she thought. Barrow makes use of his new privileges as a member of the Metropolitan Club. And Cleary and former-nun Harriett continue their burgeoning business partnership into their personal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few words on Rodney Ascher’s “The Nightmare”, a risible piece of documentary filmmaking</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/a-few-words-on-rodney-aschers-the-nightmare-a-risible-piece-of-documentary-filmmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/a-few-words-on-rodney-aschers-the-nightmare-a-risible-piece-of-documentary-filmmaking/</guid>
      <description>Rodney Ascher’s infamous “Room 237” explored the possible hidden meanings within Stanley Kubrick’s treatment of “The Shining”. While each theory examined in the film became crazier and crazier, there was at least a commitment to analyse the ideas via extended footage from the film. Although never pushing back against the testimony, its documentation of its subjects was worthy of a documentary.
With “The Nightmare”, Rodney Ascher interviews eight sufferers of sleep paralysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urgent Narrative Weakened by a Limited Visual Palette: “99 Homes” Review</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/99-homes-review-an-urgent-narrative-weakened-by-a-limited-visual-palette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/99-homes-review-an-urgent-narrative-weakened-by-a-limited-visual-palette/</guid>
      <description>From his debut feature, &amp;ldquo;Man Push Cart&amp;rdquo;, Ramin Bahrani has proven himself to be an effective teller of stories infused with social awareness and a generous sense of morality. He has the ability to sincerely and accurately examine the micro worlds that exist at the fringes of the wider world.
&amp;ldquo;99 Homes&amp;rdquo; focuses on Dennis Nash (Andrew Garfield), a labouring carpenter in Orlando facing eviction after his loan defaults. Nash unsuccessfully challenges the notice in court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Extraordinary Loneliness and Overwhelming Sensibilities of Terrence Malick: “Knight of Cups” Review</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/knight-of-cups-review-the-extraordinary-loneliness-and-sensibilities-of-terrence-malick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/knight-of-cups-review-the-extraordinary-loneliness-and-sensibilities-of-terrence-malick/</guid>
      <description>Terrence Malick&amp;rsquo;s follow up to 2013&amp;rsquo;s dazzling &amp;ldquo;To The Wonder&amp;rdquo; is another meditation on the human world and the relationships and bodies that inhabit it. It&amp;rsquo;s an introspective work intensely engendering the world he interacts with.
Malick&amp;rsquo;s stylistic choices in &amp;ldquo;Knight of Cups&amp;rdquo; will come as no surprise to anyone familiar with his work and will do little to endear those who have been alienated by it in the past. It acts as a continued mood piece from “To The Wonder”, only this time there is more to distract him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“American Sniper” Damns the Country That Produced Chris Kyle</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/american-sniper-damns-the-country-that-produced-chris-kyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/american-sniper-damns-the-country-that-produced-chris-kyle/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who sees &amp;ldquo;American Sniper&amp;rdquo; as token patriotism is either unfamiliar with Eastwood&amp;rsquo;s other work—work that regularly challenges the role of masculinity and violence buried in the American psyche—or is incapable of reading the images Eastwood has put in front of them.
Eastwood is not interested in the politics of the Iraq occupation because Kyle wasn&amp;rsquo;t. But he does damn its personal violence and the country that produced it.
The film is shot entirely from Kyle&amp;rsquo;s perspective and the final act is pure Kyle fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Inside Out” is a Reductive Take on Our Emotional Capacity</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/inside-out-is-a-reductive-take-on-our-emotional-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/inside-out-is-a-reductive-take-on-our-emotional-capacity/</guid>
      <description>At its best, &amp;ldquo;Inside Out&amp;rdquo; is a reminder of how melancholy infects memories once we realise there will come a day when we can&amp;rsquo;t produce any more.
It is also a sincere—apparently—attempt to encourage empathy.
Matt Zoller Seitz wrote that it attempts to normalise sadness:
 &amp;ldquo;Inside Out&amp;rdquo; stands in opposition to an entire culture that tells people that happiness is the highest, best and sometimes only permissible emotion, and that sadness is an obstacle to being happy, and that we should concentrate all of our emotional and cultural energy on trying to eradicate sadness so that everyone can be happy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow vision and storytelling makes the latest “Macbeth” a weak cinematic exploration</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/shallow-vision-and-storytelling-makes-the-latest-macbeth-a-weak-cinematic-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/shallow-vision-and-storytelling-makes-the-latest-macbeth-a-weak-cinematic-exploration/</guid>
      <description>Justin Kurzel’s &amp;ldquo;Macbeth&amp;rdquo; opens with the funeral of Macbeth and Lady Macbeth’s child. It’s common for writers to add scenes to Shakespeare that help render their telling unique and develop strands of his work that have yet to be explored.
The decision to include this is a bold move and suggests a particular subtext to the interpretation that will follow. That it never is, through dialogue or performance, is emblematic of an interpretation lacking in direction and depth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scared and Thinking Maybe We Ain&#39;t That Young Anymore; 40 Years of “Born To Run”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/scared-and-thinking-maybe-we-aint-that-young-anymore-40-years-of-born-to-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/scared-and-thinking-maybe-we-aint-that-young-anymore-40-years-of-born-to-run/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Thunder Road&amp;rdquo; was my introduction to Springsteen. I&amp;rsquo;d heard his music plenty of times before, I knew &amp;ldquo;Dancing in the Dark&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hungry Heart&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m On Fire&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Born To Run&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;Thunder Road&amp;rdquo; was the first of his song that stuck.
The opening verse was so vivid and pained. It was the song that made me want something more. It made me fearful of time and death and wasted opportunities. Through the song, he makes promises to his lover, he even signs off with &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a town full of losers and I&amp;rsquo;m pulling out of here to win.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Letter Circus “Aesthesis” Review; Reduced discussion of spatial awareness</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/dead-letter-circus-aesthesis-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/dead-letter-circus-aesthesis-review/</guid>
      <description>After the dire operatics of &amp;ldquo;This Is The Warning&amp;rdquo; and the buzzing electronica of &amp;ldquo;The Catalyst Fire&amp;rdquo;, Dead Letter Circus have released their third album, &amp;ldquo;Aesthesis&amp;rdquo;.
The greatness of a musician is more than the skill of performance—it&amp;rsquo;s in the skill of creation and the self-challenge of emotional exploration. This is why artists in general occupy the place they do in society as the honesty involved with artistic creation, including the honesty of self-criticism, isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Magic Mike XXL” review: Feminism and the Death of the Author.</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/magic-mike-xxl-feminism-and-death-of-the-author/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/magic-mike-xxl-feminism-and-death-of-the-author/</guid>
      <description>I recently saw &amp;ldquo;Magic Mike XXL&amp;rdquo; at the cinema with a girlfriend and I can honestly say I’ve never experienced anything like it. It’s not often I go to the cinema with a girlfriend and it’s certainly not often the entire theatre is full of women. I don’t remember seeing a single male. I could feel the anticipation in the air as I was taking my seat, my friend and I already giggling and fidgeting like school girls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Awesome Imagery of Steven Spielberg&#39;s “War of the Worlds”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-awesome-imagery-of-steven-spielbergs-war-of-the-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-awesome-imagery-of-steven-spielbergs-war-of-the-worlds/</guid>
      <description>I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen Steven Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;War of the Worlds&amp;rdquo; since the cinema in 2005. While the overall film isn&amp;rsquo;t very strong, there&amp;rsquo;s some beautiful visuals going on.
I really love this through-the-broken-glass motif, which for most of the movie is used to show Tom Cruise&amp;rsquo; Ray as the focal point, not only of the shot but of his own being.
First time. Second time. Third time. Ray thinks beyond himself and sees what really matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret connections, past lives, colour and “Sense8”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-past-lives-and-colour-of-sense8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/the-past-lives-and-colour-of-sense8/</guid>
      <description>After watching &amp;ldquo;Sense8&amp;rdquo;, Netflix&amp;rsquo; new series from Andy and Lana Wachowski, I was struck by its sincerity and its confidence in directing viewers around the world.
They show us snapshots from around the world of different cultures living. Many times doing nothing more than, just simply living in a moment. &amp;ldquo;Sense8&amp;rdquo; is all about these moments.
The character of Nomi (Jamie Clayton) is a deeply personal piece of writing but she is simply one of many characters who have lived double lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“John Wick” review: A Gorgeous Meditation on Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/john-wick-a-gorgeous-meditation-on-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/john-wick-a-gorgeous-meditation-on-life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;John Wick&amp;rdquo; is the most visually appealing action film I have ever seen.
Generally speaking, I don’t like action films. They don’t interest me in the slightest. The tired story lines and boring “at the edge of your seat” chase scenes that have been replicated poorly countless times over leave me yawning rather than gripping at anything. It just doesn’t do it for me. John Wick is different. John Wick is beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“E.T. The Extra Terrestrial” — Universal Languages &amp; Humanist Filmmaking</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/e-t-universal-languages-humanist-filmmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/e-t-universal-languages-humanist-filmmaking/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;E.T. The Extra Terrestrial&amp;rdquo; is a film where all of its cinematic elements serve to deepen the screenplay&amp;rsquo;s subtext. It is a confident and sincere piece of filmmaking that speaks universal languages.
It focuses on what I think are Spielberg&amp;rsquo;s two favourite themes: the family &amp;amp; understanding. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that his two films that explore these themes the most, this and &amp;ldquo;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&amp;rdquo;, are films based on alien encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Let Me In”: Needlessly asserting gender and discounting queerness</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/let-me-in-asserting-heterosexuality-where-its-not-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/let-me-in-asserting-heterosexuality-where-its-not-needed/</guid>
      <description>I was moved to re-watch &amp;ldquo;Let The Right one In&amp;rdquo; after reading Kyle Turner&amp;rsquo;s great write up on its queer and transgender themes.
With this in mind, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating film to explore, very tender, and sincere. The genderlessness of both lead characters is made very apparent (below), as is their acceptance of attraction of each other.
Lina Leandersson as Eli in &amp;ldquo;Let The Right one In&amp;rdquo;.
Kåre Hedebrant as Oskar in &amp;ldquo;Let The Right one In&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juror Number Eight in “Twelve Angry Men”: Cutting a Lonely Figure</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/12-angry-men-juror-number-eight-cutting-a-lonely-figure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/12-angry-men-juror-number-eight-cutting-a-lonely-figure/</guid>
      <description>When I can&amp;rsquo;t think of anything to watch I put on Sidney Lumet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;12 Angry Men&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it more times than I can count and it still keeps me interested. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it enough to start disliking some elements of Miller&amp;rsquo;s writing:
 when it&amp;rsquo;s finally 11-1 in favour of not guily, I don&amp;rsquo;t like the way Juror Nine proclaims &amp;ldquo;Eleven to one!&amp;rdquo;, or when Juror Eight reminds Juror Three that he&amp;rsquo;s alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is right about the Best Films of the Decade so far?</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/who-is-right-about-the-best-films-of-the-decade-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/who-is-right-about-the-best-films-of-the-decade-so-far/</guid>
      <description>As we find ourselves in the middle of the decade, there&amp;rsquo;s been plenty of articles on the cinematic legacy of this decade, it&amp;rsquo;s early works and what this means for the remaining five years.
Film publications are getting in early, publishing &amp;ldquo;Best Films of the Decade so far&amp;rdquo; lists, which as you can guess, are arbitrary and kind of pointless.
What is interesting is analysing the results across the different publications, from the critical to the popular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Her Best Films of 2014</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/her-best-films-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/her-best-films-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>Before I jump into my 2015 best of list I’d like to begin by apologising to our legions of readers (ie. Mum) for how late this post is. I can assure you there is a good reason behind my tardiness - I just couldn’t bring myself to write my list when there was tickets to see Birdman sitting in my pocket. Way back at the beginning of December ‘14 we had booked “advanced screening” tickets to see Birdman in the first week of January 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Post-Production Process: Namibia Nine, Part I</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/audio-post-production-process-namibia-nine-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/audio-post-production-process-namibia-nine-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts on the process, input and output of audio post-production. This will cover sound design, edit and mix.
Introduction Project: The Namibia Nine
Director: Andrea K M Capere
Story: In the 1980s, with Namibia crippled by political persecutions and economic depression, nine Namibians escape to the United States to study at Pacific Lutheran University in Seattle, Washington. This is their story.
Style: Documentary
File delivery: Zip folder featuring:
 Master Edit (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there any value in making &#39;Worst-Of&#39; lists?</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/is-there-any-value-in-making-worst-of-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/is-there-any-value-in-making-worst-of-lists/</guid>
      <description>No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I edited Steven Soderbergh&#39;s “The Knick” into an 8-hour film</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/i-edited-steven-soderberghs-the-knick-into-an-8-hour-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/i-edited-steven-soderberghs-the-knick-into-an-8-hour-film/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an admirer of Steven Soderbergh&amp;rsquo;s THE KNICK and I&amp;rsquo;ve written about my appreciation of his blocking work and the show&amp;rsquo;s dialogue before.
When the first season was finished, I knew I wanted to do something to explore the work as a whole. My initial thought was to drain the colour so it could serve as more of an artifact and to make the blocking and use of shadow the primary visual focus (and because, as Woody Allen&amp;rsquo;s Val states in Hollywood Ending, New York is a black &amp;amp; white city).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we&#39;re watching when we watch “The Knick”</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/what-were-watching-when-we-watch-the-knick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/what-were-watching-when-we-watch-the-knick/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Steven Soderbergh&amp;rsquo;s THE KNICK since Cinemax announced the show. Soderbergh has always been one of my favourite filmmakers. Even when the content isn&amp;rsquo;t interesting, he does enough with his staging and colour hues to make it interesting.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a fan of television&amp;rsquo;s format or its story arcs. The open-ended nature of the writing doesn&amp;rsquo;t interest me and that the final point of consumption is a small box usually means the director doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to think about filling the image with anything interesting beyond the direct action of the scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Ida”, the revolutionary human soul</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/ida-the-revolutionary-human-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/ida-the-revolutionary-human-soul/</guid>
      <description>“Ida” ends with a violent shot. The camera is hand-held for the first time. It shakes with each of Ida&amp;rsquo;s steps.
She walks down a long road back to the convent. The black road indifferent to the greyed countryside it snakes through. She&amp;rsquo;s been here before but this time it&amp;rsquo;s different.
Ida now sees that all things are relative, not absolute. So why does she return to the church?
She&amp;rsquo;s coming back to fuck up the establishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Best Films of 2014</title>
      <link>https://filmaday.com.au/post/his-best-films-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 11:48:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filmaday.com.au/post/his-best-films-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>In no particular order.
Ida Pawel Pawlikowski&amp;rsquo;s Ida is an intensely personal film made up of austere images and profound depth. Returning to his homeland, Pawlikowsky explores themes of guilt and identity, intrinsic to modern Poland, through Ida, a novitiate nun preparing to take her vows who finds out she is Jewish.
Composing his images with the actors in the lower-third of the frame, he uses the space above as weight on the characters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>